먹어봐, 피비
Here you go, Pheebs.
Who wants one of my
special home-baked brownies?
맛있는 브라우니 먹을 사람?
I'll have one.
- 하나 줘
- 나도
- 됐어
- 안 먹을래
-That's okay.
-I'm not having one.
No, no. It's just my tooth.
이가 아파서 그래
-All right.
-I'll have one.
- 다시 줘
- 먹을래
So you need a dentist?
I've got a good one.
괜찮은 치과 의사
아는데 소개해줄까?
Thanks. I have a good one too.
I just can't see him.
좋은 의사야 나도 알지만
갈 수가 없는 거야
돈 꾸고 떼 먹은 게
분명해
See, that is the problem
with invisible dentists.
왜 못 가는데?
Why can't you go to him?
Because every time I go
to the dentist, somebody dies.
왜냐하면...
치과 갈 때마다 누군가 죽거든
That's so weird.
Every time I go to the dentist...
이상하다, 난 치과 갈 때마다
위생사 블라우스 들여다보는데
... I look down the hygienist's blouse.
피비, 그러니까...
뭐라구?
What?
처음엔 매리 이모,
다음엔 우체부 존
First it was my Aunt Mary.
And then there was John, my mailman.
그 다음엔 카우보이
알바이노 밥이 죽었어
And then my cowboy friend, Albino Bob.
And all these people actually died?
그 사람들이
진짜 죽은거야?
치료받던 그 순간에!
Yes. While I was in the chair.
내가 이를 열심히 닦는 건
생명 구하기 차원이라구
That's why I take care of my teeth.
It's not about oral hygiene.
I floss to save lives.
그 사람들이 죽은 시점이랑
네가 치과 간 시점이 같긴 해도
Come on, you didn't kill anybody.
These people just happened to die
when you went to the dentist.
그건 우연일 뿐이야
It's just a coincidence.
한번 말해볼게
Tell that to them.
Oh, you can't! They're dead!
죽었으니 못하겠구나!
The One With the Giant Poking Device
Thanks, Gunther.
고마워요, 건터
- 안녕!
Can I get a napkin too?
냅킨도 주실래요?
Oh, like you don't already
have everything.
다른 건 다 가졌다
이건가?
피비, 그렇게 아프면
치과에 가봐, 가보라니까
You're in pain. Would you just
go to the dentist? Just go.
Fine. But if you're my next victim...
좋아, 알았다구
대신 네가 다음 희생자라면
물귀신 돼서 나 끌고 가진 마
...don't come back as a poltergeist
who sucks me into the TV set.
알았어
I promise.
놀러오는 건 봐줄게
Although, don't feel
like you can't visit.
챈들러 있어?
Hey, is Chandler here?
아니, 없는걸
No. No, he's not.
재니스랑 전남편이
키스하는 걸 조이가 봤대
You guys, Joey just saw
Janice kissing her ex-husband.
What?
뭐?
챈들러한텐 어떻게
얘기할 거야?
What are you gonna do?
How are you gonna tell Chandler?
생각해봤는데
제일 좋은 방법은...
I was thinking about that.
I think the best way would be...
안 하는 거야
...to not.
알고 있으면
다 얘기해줘야지
Joey, if you know about this,
you have to tell him.
그건 사형선고나 똑같아
It'll kill him.
It'll just kill him.
나 치과 갈 때까지 기다려
내가 죽일게
Wait till I go to the dentist.
Maybe I'll kill him.
못난이 벌거숭이가 해먹 샀네
언제 봐도 오싹한 저 살들!
I think Naked Guy's using a hammock.
It's like a Play-Doh fat factory.
I'm going to the dentist.
So listen...
나 치과 간다
그러니까 조심들하라구
...just be on the lookout for anything
that you could fall into...
무슨 일이 닥치든
어떤 경우가 생기든
...or that can fall on you...
...or....
All right, just look out!
암튼 조심해
그리고 이 말은...
꼭 해주고 싶은데...
And I also just want to....
I just want to tell you all that....
박물관에 잠깐
갔다와야겠어
I have a problem. I have to go
into work for a few hours.
꼬마들이 호모사피엔스
전시물을 건드렸대
Some kids messed up
the Homo sapien display.
뭘 어쨌길래?
What did they do?
'사피엔스'란 글자를
지운 데다
They painted over the word
"sapien," for one thing.
모형 위치를 바꿔놨대
말 안 해도 알겠지?
Then they rearranged the figures.
Let's just leave it at that.
- 내가 벤을 봐줘야겠네?
- 부탁하려던 참이었어
Do you want me to watch Ben for you?
That's what I was gonna ask.
Thank you.
잠깐만!
난 어쩌고?
Wait, hello!
What about me?
You. You want to watch Ben?
왜? 벤을 보려고?
그게 좋겠다
That would be great!
I just asked Monica...
모니카는 워낙 한가하니까
부탁했던 거지
... because I know how empty
her life is.
- 로스
- 응?
I got a science question.
궁금한 거 있어
If the Homo sapiens were, in fact,
"homo" sapiens...
호모사피엔스가
정말로 '호모'였다면
...is that why they're extinct?
그래서 멸종한 걸까?
호모사피엔스도 사람이야
Joey, Homo sapiens are people.
Hey, I'm not judging.
편견은 없다구
Look, Benny! Spoon!
벤, 수저다!
수저!
Spoon!
Come on. All right, you know what?
I think he's bored.
있잖아...
재미없나봐
Here. You wanna play
the airplane game?
벤, 비행기 놀이할까?
레이첼 고모한테 보여주자
You wanna show Rachel?
Come here.
재밌는 거 하자
You wanna do something fun? Okay.
You're so brave.
You're so brave! Yes, you are.
씩씩하다, 씩씩해
정말 씩씩하구나
-You're so brave.
-You're okay.
괜찮을 거야
이제 내려놓자
He's fine.
Let's just put him down.
이리 와라, 아가
착하지?
Come here, babe.
Yes, you're such a good boy.
애한테 어쩜 그래?
How could you do that to him?!
Ross trusted me! What's he gonna say?
로스가 뭐라 그러겠어?
말 안 하면 되지
뭐가 걱정이야?
Nothing, because we're not
telling him.
- 안 해?
- 그래
-We're not?
-No.
좋은 생각이야
All right, I like that.
우린 괜찮을 거야
So we're okay.
We're okay, aren't we?
괜찮긴? 혹 났어
혹 났다구!
No, we're not okay.
There's a bump.
What bump?
Oh, my God! Well, push it in!
Push it in!
어떡해?
눌러서 집어넣어
말 되는 소릴 해
I cannot push it in!
Okay, we're gonna need a distraction.
- 딴 데 정신 팔게 해야돼
- 그래
That's it.
I got it!
- 맞다!
- 뭔데?
오빠가 들어서자마자
The second Ross walks in...
...take him to your bedroom
and do whatever you do...
네가 방으로 데려가서
혼을 쏙 빼주는 거야
...that makes him go "rheeeee!"
됐어
Or...
...we could put a hat on his head.
모자를 씌우면 어때?
A hat! Yes! We need a hat! Where
are we gonna find a tiny little hat?
모자! 좋아!
- 모자가 있어야겠네
- 그래
작은 모자를
어디서 구하지?
곰 인형 있잖아?
I'll get Rainy Day Bear!
Because he'll know what to do?
처음부터 포기하자구?
넌 천재야
Oh, my God.
You're a genius!
It's kind of sewn on.
- 꿰매져 있어
- 줘봐
Give it. Give it.
정말 지옥이 따로 없어
It's just like a bloodbath
in here today!
Hey, hold on a second.
Hold on a second.
잠깐만!
Do you think these pearls are nice?
이 진주 괜찮지?
산악 자전거가 더 좋대두
I'd prefer a mountain bike.
재니스 생일이 다가와
특별한 선물을 해주고 싶어
Janice's birthday's coming.
I wanna get her something special.
- 들어가자
- 잠깐!
-Come in here with me.
-Wait!
특별한 선물이랬지?
You wanna get her something special?
Get her flowers.
꽃이나 사탕을 줘
껌도 괜찮고
Get her candy. Get her gum.
Girls love gum.
여자들은 껌 좋아해
That's a good idea. "Dear Janice:
Have a Hubba-Bubba birthday."
좋은 생각이군
'재니스, 선물 정말 웃겼지?'
진지한 선물 줄 거라구
I'd like to get her something serious.
You want something serious.
진지한 선물 말야?
뭐가 좋을까?
그럼...
You know what you should do?
You should get her one of those...
... barium enemas.
관장약 어때?
엄청 진지하지 않아?
Those are dead serious.
Look, I'm gonna go in here.
And you don't buy me anything, ever!
들어갈 테니까 나한텐
선물할 생각도 하지 마
안돼, 들어가면 안돼
You can't! You can't.
You can't buy her pearls.
진주 사주지 마
안된다구
You just can't, you can't,
you can't!
왜?
Why not?
Oh, God.
할 수 없군
그게 말이지...
Here's the thing.
This is the thing.
Okay, the thing is
그게 말야...
- 그게 있잖아
- '그게' 뭔데?
What is the thing?
'침대의 왕'에 갔다가
I went down to the
Mattress King's showroom...
...and I saw Janice kissing
her ex-husband.
재니스가 전남편이랑
키스하는 걸 봤어
What?
뭐?
사무실에서 말이야
They were in his office.
그럴 리 없어
나랑 사귀는데?
She wouldn't do that.
She's with me.
I'm telling you, I saw it.
내가 똑똑히 봤다니까
잘못 본 거야
잘못 봤다구
Well, you're wrong.
You're wrong.
아니라니까
차라리 그랬음 좋겠어
I'm not wrong.
I wish I was.
I'm sorry.
어쩌냐?
관장약 얘기 나올 만하지?
Bet that barium enema
doesn't sound so bad now.
It makes more sense as an ensemble.
And it takes the focus off the hat.
이러는 게 모양새가 낫지
시선도 분산시키고 말야
Oh! You're alive!
You're alive!
살아있었구나!
아무도 안 죽을
거라고 했잖아
I promised you no one
would die, didn't l?
아직 몰라, 전화 좀 쓸게
아는 사람한테 다 걸어볼래
We'll see about that. Can I use your
phone to call everyone I know?
돈 없는데 잘됐다
실컷 써
Sure. We have no money. Go ahead.
Hey, you're not dead!
Okay, see you.
너 안 죽었구나
잘 있어
몬... 카
Monica.
내 이름 부른 거야?
들었어?
Oh, my God! He just said my name!
Did you hear that?
그래
몬카 '쿵! '
Monica bang!
Okay, I heard that.
얘 좀 봐라?
'모니카 쿵'이랬니?
Did he just say, "Monica bang"?
이 나쁜 배신자!
Oh, my God! He's gonna rat me out!
Monica bang!
몬카 쿵!
아가, 그런 말하면 못써
입에 담을 가치도 없단다
Sweetie, you need to stop
saying that now.
It's no big deal.
It's not even worth mentioning.
고모들도 맨날 그래
볼래?
You see? We all do it all the time.
See? Watch this.
- 벤!
- 저기 봐봐
모니카 쿵!
모두 모두 쿵!
Monica bang!
Everybody bang!
Ben bang!
벤 쿵!
레이첼 쿵!
Rachel bang!
쿵 해! 레이첼!
Bang, Rachel! Bang!
-Oh, isn't it fun?
-Look at that!
- 재밌지?
- 봤지? 봤지?
We all do it!
다 이러고 살아
-Okay, I'm stopping now.
-Are you okay?
- 그만 할래
- 괜찮아?
You know, if it's not
a headboard, it's just not worth it.
침대 머리에 찍힐 때에
비하면 장난이지
How's my Bing-a-ling?
자기 나 왔지롱
있잖아...
I don't know.
말해봐
You tell me.
Anything you want to tell me?
할 말 있지 않아?
Because if you....
You should
아마 있을 텐데
있을 거야
You would tell me.
왜 눈을 똥그랗게
뜨고 그래?
Why are your eyes so wide?
You tell me.
옛날 애인이랑 만나놓고
찔려서 그러나?
Maybe it's because I was just
fooling around with my ex.
아냐, 아냐
그건 당신이지!
Oh, no. That was you!
- 맙소사!
- 그래
Oh, my God!
-All right!
-How did you know?
- 어떻게 알았어?
- 조이가 키스하는 걸 봤대
Joey told me. He saw you two kissing.
In the park?
공원에서?
No. In his office.
How many kisses were there?
아니, 사무실에서!
몇 번이나 한 거야?
Just those two!
- 딱 두 번이야
- 대체 왜?
Why?
키스를 왜 했어?
말이나 돼?
Why was there kissing?
There should be no kissing!
미안해, 자기야
정말 정말...
Oh, I'm sorry, honey.
I'm so, so....
I'm so, so sorry. I just....
정말 정말 미안해
그게...
내가 왜 그랬지?
너무 숨이 차
What happened was l....
I can't breathe.
Can you get me a bag or something?
봉지 같은 거 없어?
Here. Here.
여기 있어
It's the receipt.
- 웬 영수증?
- 이리 줘
I'll take it.
이제 대답해줘
Look, I've got to know.
나랑 끝난 거야?
Are you finished with me?
Are you finished with him?
그 놈이랑 끝난 거야?
Do you still love him?
아직도 사랑해?
Do you still love me?
날 사랑해?
All right, look...
좋아
...I'm gonna need an actual
answer here, okay?
똑바로 대답하라구
So which is it?
누구야?
그 놈? 나?
Him or me?
I don't know.
모르겠어
살아있으면서
왜 안 받고 그래?
Okay, if you're alive,
you answer your phone!
밥 먹기 전에 아이스크림
먹은 거 안 이를 테니까
Okay, Ben, I won't tell your daddy
that you had ice cream before dinner...
...if you won't tell him about
our little bonking incident.
가벼운 접촉 사고도
비밀이다
모니카, 큰 건 벤이 뇌물이
뭔지도 모른단 거고
Number one, I don't think Ben
understands the concept of bribery.
작은 건...
And number two, I
What?
왜?
You said "number two."
'작은 거'랬잖아?
I also said "number one."
- '큰 것'도 말했어
- 알아
I know.
Hey, everyone!
- 나 왔어
- 안녕?
How's my little boy?
벤은 잘 놀았어?
He's perfect.
Aren't you, Ben?
- 그럼, 맞지, 벤?
- 잘 놀았어
-He's never been better.
-What did you do, take him whaling?
고래라도 잡으러 가?
Monica.
몬카
Oh, my God! He just said your name!
That's great! Good job, Ben!
와! 네 이름을 말했어
잘 했어, 벤
몬카 쿵!
Monica bang!
That's right.
맞아, 털썩 주저앉으면
그런 소리나겠지
That's what I'd sound like
if I exploded.
The curse is broken!
I called everybody I know...
야호! 저주가 풀렸어
전화해봤는데 다들 살아있어
...and everyone is alive!
- 이런...
- 왜?
Ugly Naked Guy looks awfully still.
못난이 벌거숭이가
꼼짝도 안 해
어떡해?
내가 죽인 거야
My God, I killed another one!
저주가 강해졌나봐
저런 덩치가 쓰러지다니!
The curse is getting stronger too,
to bring down something that big.
Maybe he's just taking a nap.
자는 걸지도 몰라
아침부터 꼼짝도
안 하는데도?
I'm telling you,
he hasn't moved since this morning.
We should call somebody.
신고라도 하자
벌거숭이를 쭉 지켜봤는데
꼼짝도 안 하더라고 말할래?
Tell them the naked guy we stare at
isn't moving?
생사 확인은 해야잖아?
We've got to find out if he's alive.
근데 방법이 없는걸?
How are we gonna do that?
There's no way.
Well, there is one way.
창이 열려있으니
방법은 있어
His window's open.
I say...
찔러보면 되지
...we poke him.
중국요리 시킬 때마다
쓸데없이 젓가락 모았잖아?
You know how we save
all those chopsticks...
...for no reason
when we get Chinese food?
근데?
쓸데가 생겼어
Well, now we got a reason.
What?
뭔데?
We're fashioning a very long
poking device.
긴 장대를 만들 거거든
All right.
그렇군
Hey, what's the matter?
너 왜 그래?
I talked to Janice.
재니스한테 말했어
Oh, my God. Is she going back to him?
남편한테 돌아갈 거래?
She doesn't know.
몰라, 둘 다 사랑한대
Says she loves us both.
I woke up this morning, I was in love.
오늘 아침까지만 해도
사랑에 겨워 행복했다구
I was happy!
It serves me right for buying
that 12-pack of condoms.
콘돔을 왜
한 다스나 샀겠어?
재니스가 영수증을 삼켜서
이젠 환불도 안돼
And now I can't even return them,
because she choked on the receipt!
What are you gonna do?
그래서 어쩔 건데?
I don't know.
모르겠어
너라면 어쩌겠어?
You know? What would you do?
It doesn't matter what I'd do.
- 내 생각이 뭐가 중요해?
- 얘기해봐
Come on. Come on. Tell me.
All right...
좋아
...you probably won't want
to hear this...
듣기 싫을진 몰라도
만약 나라면...
내가 그 상황이면
... but if it was me,
and this is just me...
... I'd bow out.
- 순순히 물러나겠어
- 뭐?
What?
What are you talking about?
그게 무슨 소리야?
둘 사이엔 애도 있어
They have a kid together...
...you know?
가정이 있는 거라구
They're, like, a family.
And if, I don't know...
그 둘이 잘 될
기미가 보인다면
...if there's a chance
they can make that work...
... I wouldn't want to be the guy
who stood in the way.
나 같으면
방해 안 할 거야
You okay?
괜찮지?
벌거숭이 찌르러 안 갈래?
You wanna come poke a nude guy?
Well, he's finally asleep.
이제 잠들었어
About that bump on his head....
근데 머리에 혹이 났던데?
Are you sure it's a new bump?
그게 혹이라고 생각해?
No offense, but I've always thought
of Ben as a fairly bumpy-headed child.
밉다는 건 아니고
벤이 짱구이긴 하잖아?
It's okay if he bumps his head.
Kids bump their heads all the time.
괜찮아, 혹이면 어때?
그러면서 크는 거야
It was your first time babysitting.
You did your best.
처음인데
실수할 수도 있지
I did!
실수?
I know.
알아, 좀더 신경써서
지켜봐야 한단 거야
You just have to watch them
all the time.
한눈 안 팔았어, 모니카가
벤 머릴 박는 것도 봤다구
I did! I watched! I watched!
I watched Monica bang his head
against that thing!
Monica did it?
모니카가 그랬어?
- 모니카!
- 응?
Did you notice anything weird
about Ben today?
벤이 오늘 좀
이상하지 않았어?
No, why?
아니, 왜?
벤이랑 알파벳 노래
부르면서 놀았거든
I was just playing with him, and we
were doing the "Alphabet Song"...
평소엔 잘 외던 애가
'E'랑 'F'를 빼먹지 뭐야?
...which he's good at.
But he left out "E" and "F."
It's like they just, I don't know,
fell out of his head.
애가 좀 멍해졌어
Really?
정말?
게다가 걸음걸이도
Oh, and also, he's walking...
... kind of funny.
좀 이상해
왼발을 오른발보다
훨씬 빨리 움직여
It's like his left leg is moving
a lot faster than his right leg.
Yeah, he's in there, just....
이렇게 하더라니까
어떡해?
다 나 때문이야
Oh, my God! I wrecked your baby!
그렇게 놀려먹다
지옥 가지
I hope it's still funny
when you're in hell.
You jerk!
못됐어! 벤을 얼마나
좋아하는지 알면서!
-You know how much I love that kid!
-Monica bang! Monica bang!
몬카 쿵! 몬카 쿵!
모자 가져올게
I'll get the hat.
재니스, 할 말이 있어
그냥 끝까지 들어줘
I have something to tell you.
And I want you to let me
get through it...
... because...
물론...
쉽진 않을 거야
...it's not gonna be easy.
알았어
I think you should go back with Gary.
남편한테 돌아가
I don't want to be the guy
that breaks up a family.
당신 가정을 깨고싶지 않아
You know, when my parents split up,
it was because of that guy.
우리 부모님도 이런 경우였어
그 남잘 보면 이렇게 생각했지
Whenever I'd see him,
I'd always think...
... "You're the reason.
You are why they're not together."
'당신 때문에 부모님이
헤어지셨어'
And I hated that guy.
죽도록 미워했지
And it didn't matter how nice he was
or how happy he made my dad.
멋진 사람이고 덕분에
아빤 행복해지셨지만 말야
이것 참!
이해해
그래도 어쩔 수 없어
It's the right thing to do.
You're right.
맞아
Oh, God.
But before I can say goodbye...
하지만 떠나기 전에
이 말만은 하고 싶어
...there's something I really
need you to know.
The way I feel about you...
당신에 대한 내 감정은
...it's like I finally understand...
라이오넬 리치 노래의 의미를
깨달은 것과 같아
...what Lionel Ritchie's
been singing about.
You know?
I mean, what we have...
우리 사랑은
영화 같았단 거야
...it's like movie love.
You're my soul mate.
내 진정한 사랑...
I can't believe we're not gonna
spend the rest of our lives together.
앞으로 함께 지낼 수
없다니 믿어지지 않아
Then don't leave me.
그럼 가지 마
What?
뭐?
내가 한 말은 잊고
날 택해
Forget what I said! I was babbling!
Pick me!
No, you were right! I gotta give
my marriage another chance.
당신이 했던 말 다 옳아
다시 시작해볼 거야
말도 안돼
No, you don't!
이혼을 다시 한번
고려해봐
I say you have to give your divorce
another chance!
I'm sorry.
미안해
Don't go.
가지 마
No, I gotta go.
가야 돼
안돼!
Honey. Honey.
남들이 보잖아
-People are looking.
-I don't care.
상관없어
볼 테면 봐요!
I don't care!
그만 가볼게
Yeah, okay.
I'm leaving now.
못 가!
신발이 여기 있는걸?
You can't leave! I have your shoe!
Goodbye, Chandler Bing.
안녕, 챈들러 빙
Rachel has those in burgundy.
레이첼도 그 신발 있는데
Remember, something this big and long
will be very difficult to maneuver.
크고 긴 건 다루기가
어렵단 사실 명심해
Fortunately, I have
experience in that area.
그래도 내가 경험이
많으니 안심해
Can we please focus here? A naked
man's life hangs in the balance.
제발 집중해, 벌거숭이
목숨이 왔다갔다 한다구
I'm telling you, he's dead.
죽었다니까 그러네
What we're about to have here
is a dead fat guy on a stick!
돼지 꼬치 만들 일 있어?
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
let's poke.
신사 숙녀 여러분
찌릅시다!
Steady.
그대로, 그대로
조금 높이
Okay, a little higher.
Careful of the angle.
각도 유지하고
좋아, 좋아
창문에 접근!
Okay, okay.
We're approaching the window.
조심해서 찔러
조심해서!
Thread the needle. Thread the needle.
살아있다, 살아있어!
He's alive! He's alive!
이제 그만 찌를까?
And yet we're still poking him.
무기 철수!
Okay, retract the device!
Retract the device!
He does not look happy.
뭐 씹은 표정인데
Now he's showing us his poking device.
저 사람도 무기를
들이대고 있는데
그걸로 어디 여기까지
넘어오겠어?
Hey, that's never gonna make it
all the way over here, buddy!
I'll hold you close in my arms
당신을 내 품에 안고 싶어요
당신을 거부할 수 없어요
I can't resist your charms
And love
사랑해요
Love
I'll be a fool for you
당신을 위해선
바보가 되어도 좋아요
I'm sure
You know I don't mind
전 상관없어요
당신도 알고 있겠죠
Oh, you know I don't mind
Yes
You mean the world to me
나에겐 당신이 전부예요
Oh, I know
I know
- 알아요
I've found
- 이제야 알았어요
In you
My endless love
당신을 향한
내 끝없는 사랑
My endless love
사랑